<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Eduardo Robles Site</title>
    <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Eduardo Robles Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eduardorobles.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accessing my homelab with Cloudflare</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/accessing-homelab-with-cloudflare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/accessing-homelab-with-cloudflare/</guid>
      <description>Cloudflare Access for my Homelab
I decided to use Cloudflare to setup a Secure Web Gateway and establish some Zero Trust access for my homelab services. Cloudflare offers a great service called “Cloudflare Access”. Basically it leverages Cloudflare’s edge network to create secure web routing. Setting up this service is just a matter of running a simple daemon. Once configured you setup Cloudflare DNS to route traffic. Let’s discuss how I setup Cloudflare Access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Homelab with Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/starting-homelab-proxmox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/starting-homelab-proxmox/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning
So if you hadn’t heard of the idea of a “homelab”, let me give you the quick run down of what is a “homelab”. Basically, a homelab is a collection of technologies (hardware and software) that you install, maintain, and configure in your home. Imagine a datacenter in your home or an electronics lab can also be a homelab. At the heart of the homelab movement is the idea of tinkering and learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation of Fog Project 1.5.8</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/installation-fog-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/installation-fog-server/</guid>
      <description>Hi there!
Follow along with me in this video as I install Fog Server. To learn more about Fog Project check out there website https://fogproject.org/. The installation is done with a simple script that you download from the project website.
For this example I used Cent OS which you can get at the website here https://centos.org. You can use a Debian based OS as well but I chose Cent OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Port Forward a VNC Connection</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/ssh-port-forward-vnc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/ssh-port-forward-vnc/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wanted to access a Virtual Machine I had created on my desktop from my laptop. I had access to the desktop via SSH but I wanted access to the virtual machine. To make things more interesting I wanted to access the VM(virtual machine) via a graphical interface.
So I figured out that I could use SSH to “port forward” the VNC connection from the desktop to my laptop. It’s actually very easy and only requires a few basic SSH commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2020 Ubuntu Laptop Setup</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/2020-laptop-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/2020-laptop-update/</guid>
      <description>New Year, New Setup
Ubuntu 19.10 Desktop
I began the new year by buying a new 500GB SSD. My laptop had 2 drives: a 32GB SSD was my /root drive and a 120GB SSD was /home partition. This served me just well but obviously I would run out of space quickly if I was working with virtual machines. With a new drive I had to make the decision to start from scratch or use backups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Grub on a Dual Boot</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/fix-grub-dual-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/fix-grub-dual-boot/</guid>
      <description>I recently decided to move my Ubuntu installation from my laptop to my desktop without having to reinstall. So basically all I wanted to do is move the SSD (which had Ubuntu 19.10 installed) in my laptop to my desktop. This process is not hard at all but in my case it was a little more complicated. I wanted to do a dual boot on my desktop computer with 2 different hard drives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDuckGo Mobile Browser</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/duckduckgo-mobile-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/duckduckgo-mobile-browser/</guid>
      <description>I blogged before about switching from Firefox Focus to DuckDuckGo mobile. Now it’s been 3 weeks since I made the switch and I wanted to do a quick post about my experience.
First, it’s going great. I really like the fact that a search widget is included. I replaced the Google search with DuckDuckGo and I find myself using it a lot more. Which is great because I really like using DuckDuckGo as my default search engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Region One Cybersecurity Summit 2019</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/region-one-summit-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/region-one-summit-2019/</guid>
      <description>Region One hosted a Cybersecurity Summit for 2019 in Edinburg, TX. The event was free and I signed up to attend. It was a great event that had many great presenters. The theme of the summit was Cybersecurity on a regional level. Here are some of the talks I attended and the takeaways I got from them.
Reduce Your Cybersecurity Risk and Get Complaint with SB 820
– Develop Policy: use already established policies as blueprints – Items to invest in: Malware protection/Endpoint protection, Firewalls, IDS/IPS, Spam Filtering, Log Monitoring</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Focus</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/firefox-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/firefox-focus/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Firefox Focus for about half a year now. I came to use because I was using Chrome and simply got paranoid of what stuff Google was collecting via Chrome. So I made the switch to Firefox on my PC and started using Firefox for Android. Now before I started using Firefox Focus I was using Brave Browser for Android.
Brave Browser is a Chromium based browser that tauts privacy for the end user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on “The Alchemist” by Paulo Coelho</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/the-alchemist-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/the-alchemist-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>The Alchemist by Paulo Coelho
Since I have been reading “self-help” books my wife suggested I check out The Alchemist. Luckily she owned a copy, so I grabbed it from our bookshelf and stuffed it in my backpack. I gotta say that I really enjoyed this book. I can now see why so many people consider it a “self-help”, book. Here are a two of my favorite passages:
 My heart is afraid that it will have to suffer”, the boy told the alchemist one night as they looked up at the moonless sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on “Smarter Faster Better: The Transformative Power of Real Productivity” by Charles Duhigg</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/smarter-faster-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/smarter-faster-better/</guid>
      <description>Smarter Faster Better: The Transformative Power of Real Productivity by Charles Duhigg
I had heard so much of Charles Duhigg from many “entrepreneurial youtubers”, so naturally I became curious of his work. Most people recommend his book The Power of Habit, I even remember a colleague reading it. But I didn’t find a copy of it at my local library but I did find a copy of Smarter Faster Better instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape Rooms Challenge at STC</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/escapre-rooms-stc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/escapre-rooms-stc/</guid>
      <description>To help celebrate National CyberSecurity Awareness month the Information Security office at South Texas College created an “Escape Room” challenge. I got to participate in this years festivities. I like the challenge of doing escape rooms so one that had a cybersecurity theme seemed even more fun. The activity was quite fun despite not being able to “escape” in time.
The challenge consisted of finding the decryption key to decrypt a computer that was attacked with Ransomware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I got a Library Card in 2019</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/library-card-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/library-card-2019/</guid>
      <description>I was having a conversation with my wife and I said to her “You know, I feel like I’m getting dumber”. We both laughed out loud at my ridiculous statement, she then asked why I felt that. The reason I was l feeling like that was because I was simply spending too much time on other silly distractions. And no it wasn’t just “social media”, I tend to go down YouTube rabbit holes too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset Windows Password with Linux</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/reset-windows-password-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/reset-windows-password-linux/</guid>
      <description>Ever needed to reset your Windows password but forgot to make a Windows Reset Password disk? If so, you can easily reset a Windows Users password with a Live Linux USB. Let’s see just how easy it is to so.
If you don’t a Live Linux USB go ahead an create one. This tutorial is Ubuntu based so any Ubuntu flavor will work. And you will need a working internet connection to download software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relaunching my personal website</title>
      <link>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/relaunching-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eduardorobles.com/posts/relaunching-website/</guid>
      <description>Leaving social media
So this week I found myself falling down a crazy rabbit hole. It all happened when I watched this video on the indieweb concept. I was hooked on the idea and philosophy of the indeweb! Just recently I had been putting a lot of thought on leaving social media behind. But of course in this day and age doing that is much easier said than done. Still I had this gut feeling telling me that I just didn’t want to be on platforms like facebook any more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
